Guide to the Educational Cooperative Publishing Company of Montana records 1937-1967
Montana Historical Society
- Subject Files
  - Harvey M. Matusow case (includes text of Matusow's affidavit withdrawing accusations against Clinton Jencks of Mine-Mill Union, re continued Communist Party membership), 1955 (Box-folder 10 / 10)
  - Miles City Star (re 1948 election) (Box-folder 10 / 11)
  - Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Union (includes "A Review of Montana's 1947 State Legislature," by William Mason; Mine-Mill District #1; union election circulars' Clinton Jencks controversy; factional fight with Steelworkers Union; union publications), 1947-1956 (Box-folder 10 / 12)
  - Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Union strikes, 1951 (Box-folder 11 / 1)
  - Missouri Valley Authority [MVA] (includes correspondence with Jerome G. Locke; Regional Committee for MVA; clippings), 1944-1951 (Box-folder 11 / 2)
  - Gen. William "Billy" Mitchell court martial (includes "The Saga of Billy Mitchell," by Jack Pearl re military air power), 1956 (Box-folder 11 / 3)
  - The Montana Corporation (includes articles of incorporation; clippings), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 11 / 4)
  - Montana development (includes correspondence and other materials re Knowles Dam, Paradise Dam and Yellowtail Dam; speeches by E.O. Sowerwine; legislative bills; State Planning Board newsletters; clippings), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 11 / 5)
  - Montana Industrial Health Committee (re drive to cover silicosis and other industrial illnesses under Workmen's Compensation Act; includes correspondence, proposed legislation, petitions, clippings; also includes "Directory of Labor Organizations in Montana"; history of Farmers Union Oil Company; Constitution and By-laws of International Brotherhood of Bookbinders #101; brochure on Educational Co-operative Publishing Company of Montana), 1952 (Box-folder 11 / 6-7)
  - Montana power development (re Columbia Valley Administration, power transmission lines, public power, hydro-electric dams, Rural Electric Association; includes correspondence, speeches, minutes), 1946 (Box-folder 11 / 8)
  - Montana State Dept. of Labor (re bill creating Dept. of Labor as separate entity), 1951 (Box-folder 11 / 9)
  - Montana State Laboratory Building [Cogswell Building] (to house laboratories of Highway Commission, Water Conservation Board, Board of Health, Food and Drug Division, Industrial Hygenic Division, Sanitary Engineering Division, and Livestock Sanitary Board), 1946 (Box-folder 11 / 10)
  - Montana State Training School and Hospital, Boulder (includes minutes of Governor's Committee on Mental Health; The Roundup, May, 1951; clipping on overcrowding), 1951, 1953 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
  - Montana State University, Missoula (re controversy with Montana Kaiman; speech at Charter Day Convocation), 1949-1950, 1966 (Box-folder 12 / 2)
  - Montana State University, Missoula: drinking (clippings), 1955 (Box-folder 12 / 3)
  - Montana State University, Missoula: equestrian class, 1957 (Box-folder 12 / 4)
  - Montana State University, Missoula: family housing project, 1954 (Box-folder 12 / 5)
  - Montana State University, Missoula: Dr. James Ford resignation as Dean of School of Journalism, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 12 / 6)
  - Montana State University, Missoula: miscellany, 1954 (Box-folder 12 / 7)
  - Montana State Federation of Labor (includes proceedings; resolutions; reports; correspondence with affiliated unions; financial records; legislative summaries), 1912-1957 (Box-folder 12 / 8)
  - Montana State Federation of Labor: essay contest (topic "Do We Need Labor Unions in a Democracy?"), 1948 (Box-folder 12 / 9)
  - Montana State Federation of Labor: Executive Board (includes report, correspondence, resolutions, minutes), 1928, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 12 / 10-11)
  - Montana State Federation of Labor: nominations, 1950, 1952 (Box-folder 12 / 12)
  - Montana. Subversive and Un-American Activities, Interim Committee to Investigate, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 12 / 13)
  - James E. Murray, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 12 / 14)
  - National Youth Administration, 1940 (Box-folder 12 / 15)
  - Nurse licensing, 1952 (Box-folder 12 / 16)
  - James F. O'Connor, 1940 (Box-folder 12 / 17)
  - Oil issues (primarily correspondence with other states; also includes transcript of hearing on natural gas prices, 1955; court cases; proposed legislation), 1952-1956 (Box-folder 12 / 18)
  - Oil issues (printed material), 1951-1955 (Box-folder 13 / 1)
  - Paradise Dam (correspondents include Committee for Paradise Dam, Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes, John R. Garber, Frances Logan; also includes printed material, articles, etc.), 1957 (Box-folder 13 / 2-3)
  - Peace (includes excerpt from letter from Jeannette Rankin re World Pacifist Conference in India; article by Andre Fontaine "Raise Your Boy To Be a Soldier"), undated (Box-folder 13 / 4)
  - Power producers (re Production for Use Committee), 1929-1944 (Box-folder 13 / 5)
  - Public power projects, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 13 / 6)
  - Public utility districts, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 13 / 7)
  - Public utility districts (printed material), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 14 / 1)
  - Railroad mergers (printed material), 1960 (Box-folder 14 / 2)
  - Rural Electrification Administration contract wages, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 14 / 3)
  - Red Lodge coal char plant (re production of coal by-products by Koal Krudes Company; also includes "Results of Continuous Coal Charring Operations," by John W. Goodenbour [MS thesis, Montana State College]), 1955-1956 (Box-folder 14 / 4)
  - William Scallon (printed material), undated (Box-folder 14 / 5)
  - Technical Engineers and Architects, Association of, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 14 / 6)
  - Treasure State Industries, Inc., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 14 / 7)
  - United States. Securities and Exchange Commission, 1958 (Box-folder 14 / 8)
  - Voting techniques: Legislative session (printed material and roll calls), 1957 (Box-folder 14 / 9-10)
- Writings
  - Drafts of People's Voice articles by others, 1940-1941, 1953 (Box-folder 14 / 11)
- Miscellany
  - Miscellaneous (includes legislative bills, legislative expenses, minutes of Montana Progressive Council meeting, Rocky Mountain Sportsmen's Association resolution, circulars, cartoon), 1935-1950 (Box-folder 14 / 12-13)
- Clippings
  - Miscellaneous (includes items from Missoula Times; statement of Finnish Workers Federation on Soviet "mutual assistance pact"; "Report of Special Investigating Committees of the 26th Legislative Assembly"), 1939, 1958, undated (Box-folder 14 / 14)